Register of the Iris R. Powers papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Iris R. Powers papers
1969-1979
1972-1973
83013
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes (1.6 linear feet)
Transcripts of meetings, correspondence, writings, testimony, and printed matter relating to readjustment of American prisoners of war returning from the Vietnamese War.
Powers, Iris R.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1983.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical note
1917 Born
1969 Power's son, CWO Lowell S. Powers, reported missing after his plane crashed in Vietnam
1971 National Coordinator of National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia
1972-1973 Chairman of the Repatriation, Rehabilitation and Readjustment (Triple R) Committee
1971 Consultant to the Center for Prisoner of War Studies regarding family matters
1970-1971 Consultant to the Department of the Army
1997 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The Repatriation, Rehabilitation, and Readjustment Committee (Triple R) files consist of meeting transcripts, correspondence, writings, testimony, and printed matter accounting the treatment of American POWs (Prisoner of War) and of those missing in action (MIAs). The Personal papers file includes photographs, certificates, hearings, presentations, and printed materials on the Triple R Committee and testimonies of American POW experience in Southeast Asia.
National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia.; Prisoners of war.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Prisoners and prisons, North Vietnamese.
- Repatriation, Rehabilitation, and Readjustment (Triple R) Committee File, 1972-1973
  Scope and Contents note
  Transcripts prepared from tape recordings of the proceedings, in original order by date.
  - Triple R Committee transcript of proceedings, 1972 March-June (Text 1:1-9)
  - Triple R Committee transcript of proceedings, 1972 March-1973 March (Text 2:1-7)
  - Triple R Committee transcript of proceedings, 1973 March-May (Text 3:1-6)
  - Remarks of General Russell Ogan, 1973 May (Text 3:7)
  - National League of Families transcript of proceedings, 1973 July (Text 3:8)
    Note
    National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia, 4th Annual Meeting.
  - Presentation by Iris Powers, 1973 September (Text 3:9)
    Transcript from the Social Worker Regional Coordinator Symposium, Center for Prisoner of War Studies, San Diego, California, held from September 24th to 28th, 1973 in conjunction with the National League of Families of American Prisoners and Missing in Southeast Asia and the Development of Family Services.
- Personal Papers File, 1969-1979
  - Consultant for POW/MIA Next-of-Kin Affairs, 1969-1971 (Text 3:10)
  - Hearings on the American Prisoners of War in Southeast Asia, 1970-1971 (Text 3:11)
  - CWO Lowell S. Powers' MIA documents, 1969-1979 (Text 4:1)
  - Photographs and certificates, 1970-1971 (Text 4:2)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Text 4:3)
  - Petition to the Secretary-General of the United Nations, 1971 June (Text 4:4)
  - "Full Committee Briefing on Project Egress Recap,", 1972 October (Text 4:5)
  - Hearings on American Prisoners of War in Southeast Asia, 1972-1973 (Text 4:6)
  - "NLOF and the Development of Family Services," presentation, 1973-1974 (Text 4:7)
  - Hearings on Americans missing in Southeast Asia, 1975 (Text 4:8-9)
    Includes final report.
  - Life Magazine, "In brief for the POW, a catch-up on news from the missing years,", 1972 (Text 4:10)
    Scope and Contents
    A digest of major news events from 1965 to 1972 published in conjunction with the United States armed forces intended so that returning American POWs could acquaint themselves with events that occured during the time they were captured overseas. Published by Copley Newspapers.
  - Life Magazine, "Questions for a Peace,", 1972 November (Text 4:11)
    Features reports on the state of POW/MIAs after returning to the United States.